Guide to the Medieval manuscript fragments, [ca. 800-ca. 1800]
Medieval manuscript fragments
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Medieval manuscript fragments and objects, [ca. 800 - ca. 1600].
6532
Anonymous.
3 cubic feet.
Manuscripts
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.
Various Medieval manuscript fragments and objects.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Various items, including documents (such as Nuremberg rules for execution from 16th century, papal texts, legal statements) and fragments from books (such as parchment strips recovered from bindings, historiated initials, illuminations, and leaves drawn from various texts including the Vulgate Bible, commentaries on the Bible, breviaries, Psalters, books of hours, homilies, liturgical books with musical notation, books of law, works of Church Fathers such as Augustine and Jerome, works of classical authors such as Cicero and Livy, and works of various other authoritative authors such as Avicenna). Included is a document written on a bifolium from Thann (Alsace), dated 1499, listing saints' relics transferred from monstrances to a reliquary (here called a Tafel) in 1458 at the collegiate church of St. Thiébaut. Also, a fragment of an unidentified Lauda from the Passion of Christ, in ottava rima, probably of mid-Italian origin. It describes St. Peter's denial, the trial of Christ before Caiaphas, the crowd's verdict, the flagellation, and the humiliation.
Also included is a leaf from an antiphonal, on vellum, with a miniature of a female saint preaching. The leaf (480 x 355 mm.) is from north-central Italy, probably around Bologna, ca. 1350. It includes 7 four-line staves in red, and a large initial "A" illustrating the verse Adaperiat dominus cor vestrum (2 Macc. 4). Music and text of a later date are added in the bottom margin.
Included in addition is a framed 1288 document on vellum from Abbess Jutta von Arnsberg of Freckenhorst, Germany, concerning an annuity for goods bought in connection with the annual feast of St. Martin's. The abbess's seal is attached to the document by its original tab.
Also included is a Spanish manuscript on vellum, conveying a piece of olive grove near Cordoba, dated 10 February 1503; and a small bronze seal matrix, used to seal documents, bearing an image of an Agnus Dei with a large flag on a long crucifix, with inscription "Ecce Agnvs Dei."
Also, a remnant of a 15th-century book of hours annotated and augmented in the following centuries, with an inscription on the front pastedown dated 1768 naming one of its owners: Jean Hersmulle Duport, doctor of theology (Sorbonne), who taught physics at the Sulpician Grand Seminary of St Irenee, and then became curate of Loire, a village between Lyon and Vienne (until 1791). With eight original vellum leaves from the manuscript, most with added texts. The contents are: 1. one folio numbered 17, with the end of the Gospel lesson of St. Matthew, an inscription in a later hand, and on the verso the capital letters DE LH (the rest blank); 2. one folio with four lines of Latin religious verse in French humanist minuscule script, below which is an erased inscription that can be read in ultraviolet light (naming "Jehan Frenier," with various place-names: probably Je[h]an Frenier, cure de Saint-Martin de Maulay, near Loudun), the verso blank; 3. six folios from the end of the book, the first being the conclusion of the Suffrages but with the following added: a complete prayer in 90 rhyming couplets of French, beginning "O Iesu roy de tout le monde / En qui toute bonte abonde / Je suis ta pauvre creature / Contemplant ta saincte figure / Se tenant a grands cloux de fer... Helas quel fers, helas quelz cloux / Ils furent forges longs et groux / Pour te faire plus de martyre" (a variant was printed in 1556 in Fr. Pierre Olivier, Le Mirouer du Chrestien), followed by "Les Sept Oraisons de St. Gregoire" complete in seven Latin stanzas; this followed by an inscription, "AU NOM DIEU / AMEN CES HEURES." Many medieval manuscripts were transmitted from generation to generation and abundantly annotated. This remnant reveals the kinds of texts deemed essential in such books of private devotion but omitted, for whatever reason, from the original commissi on.
Fragment from Saint Augustine's Expositio in evangelium Johannis, from Italy, circa 1100; leaf on vellum from a breviary, Flanders, circa 1350; and leaf on vellum from a large antiphonal, from Spain, circa 1525, with elaborate Moorish strapwork design on the borders and surrounding a large initial letter O. Also, a leaf from a 16th-century antiphonal from Italy, on vellum, with decorated initials; and a leaf from another antiphonal from Italy, circa 1500, with decorated initials made with a compass.
Also, a leaf from a Book of hours (Paris, circa 1500), with a color illustration showing the coronation of the Virgin; and a fragment of a manuscript bifolium from Thomas of Breslau's Practica medicinalis, subsequently used as a binding cover in a volume, with pieces of leather straps laced through the text (Italy, late 14th century).
Fragment from a codex of Justinian, with historiated initials including the head of a woman in a blue cloak (southern France, circa 1280).
Also, the last will of Margarita de Ballis, the wife of the Count de Ballis, in Alcamo, Sicily (1408), on paper with a watermark showing a hand with a flower, commonly found on paper in Europe. Also, a historiated border on vellum from the Great Choir Book of Ferdinand and Isabella, Castile, circa 1479-1492.
Two fragments of a commentary on the Sentences of Peter Lombard, with a remark on werewolves, by Richard of Middleton (Ricardus de Mediavilla), circa 1400.
Also, a papal bull signed by Pope Innocent VIII, 1488; and a patristic manuscript in Greek, evidently a homily about St. John Chrysostom, 11th century. Also, a leaf of the Stimulus amoris by Pseudo-Bonaventure, in Old French translation, circa 1420. Two fragments in Greek, one from Gregory of Nicomedia's Sermo in S. Mariam assistentem cruci, circa 13th or 14th century, and the other the description of Jesus's entrance into Jerusalem, Matthew 21:1-19, 12th or 13th century.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Augustine, Saint, Bishop of Hippo.; Avicenna, 980-1037.; Cicero, Marcus Tullius.; Jerome, Saint, d. 419 or 20.; Jesus Christ--Passion.; John Chrysostom, Saint, -407.; Livy.; Jutta, von Arnsberg.; Duport, Jean Hersmulle, former owner.; Thomas, of Breslau. Practica medicinalis.; Justinian I, Emperor of the East, 483?-565.; Ballis, Margarita de.; Ricardus, de Mediavilla, approximately 1249-1308?; Pseudo-Bonaventure. Stimulus amoris.; Gregory, of Nicomedia, -1240.; Catholic Church--Liturgy.
Titles:
Bible -- Commentaries.; Grandes chroniques de France.; Bible. Matthew. Greek. 12th-13th century.
Subjects:
Manuscripts, Medieval.; Music--500-1400.; Music--15th century.; Music--16th century.; Legal documents.; Fathers of the church.; Authors, Classical.; Sermons.; Relics.; Women saints.
Form and Genre Terms:
Gothic scripts.; Historiated initials.; Illuminations.; Books of hours.; Breviaries.; Psalters.; Bifolia.; Antiphonaries--Italy--16th century.; Wills.; Stamps (tools)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See also the Eleze McKenzie Collection of Medieval Manuscript Leaves, #6931, http://resolver.library.cornell.edu/cgi-bin/EADresolver?id=RMM06931
NOTES
Scripts include examples of various forms of Carolingian, Praegothica, Northern and Southern Textualis, Semitextualis, Cursiva Antiquior, Cursiva, Hybrida, Semihybrida, Gothico-Antiqua.
CONTAINER LIST
- Mutilated bifolium from a glossed Vulgate Bible, Psalms 39 and 41., Ninth century.; Size: 264 x 352 mm (220 x 131 mm). (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Description: Written in Latin, on parchment with red capitals and rubrics in Carolingian script. Marginal glossing in a smaller hand (also a Carolingian script) and some staining on the second folio. Contains Psalms 39:2-13, 41:7-43.
  Provenance: Lost description by Susan Farrier, n.d. Formerly b.21.
- Leaf from Leo Magnus’ Tractatus, 75, 76., Ninth century.; Size: 385 x 254 mm (339 x 194 mm incomplete). (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Description: Written in Latin in two ruled columns on flesh side of the parchment only. In a Carolingian script and including occasional red initials, rubrication, and highlighting. Taken from a binding.
  Provenance: Lost description by Elizabeth Rowe, 1981. Formerly m.31.
  ID Number: CornellMedMS_022.jpg (a).
- One binding strip probably from a Bible containing Jerome, Matthew 3.21.1-11 and Zacharias 9.9.9., Ninth century.; Size: 309 x 12 mm (264 x 12 mm incomplete). (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Description: Narrow binding strip written in Latin on parchment in a Carolingian script with no decoration.
  Provenance: Lost description by Camille Bennett, May 1979. Formerly o.33.
- Mutilated bifolium from a lectionary including readings from Acts 3:9-10., Ninth century.; Size: 56 x 362/192 mm (56 x 161 mm incomplete). (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Description: Written in Latin on parchment in a Carolingian script and featuring some red rubrication.
  Provenance: Formerly 007.
  ID Number: CornellMedMS_014_001.jpg (a).
- Leaf containing capitula for 1. Corinthians 3:16-4:17 on recto and Bible fragment on verso., Ninth century.; Size: 341 x 166/101 mm (282 x 73 mm). (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Description: Written in Latin on parchment in a Carolingian script.
  Provenance: Acquired by George Lincoln Burr. Formerly folder v.40.
- Leaf with commentary on Luke 7:36, probably from Germany., Ninth to tenth century.; Size: 205 x 148/176 mm. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Description: Written in Latin on parchment. The script is Carolingian and of the Alcuin School of Tours. Fragment contains commentary on Luke 7.36, possibly from a book of Sermons. Probably brought to the abbey of St Maximin by Ada, sister of Charlemagne.
  Provenance: Purchased by George Lincoln Burr. Burr’s notes read: ‘Manuscript fragments of about 800 AD taken from an old book ( CUL’s copy of the Bibliae Moraliztus of Berchorius of Poitiers – 7546 G75) and to be restored to that volume after photographing them for the Pope’s Biblical Commission’; and another reads, ‘[…] Even more interesting than the book itself is the old MS with which the monks of St. Maximim to whom this copy belonged, have lined the binding. It is a fragment of a Bible of the ninth century, which was perhaps brought to St. Maximim by Ada, sister of Charlemagne. The script is clearly (so Dr. Loew convinced me) the work of Alcuin’s School of Tours […]’. Note that this manuscript fragment was never returned to the binding of Bibliae Moraliztus.
  ID Number: CornellMedMS_010_001.jpg (a); CornellMedMS_010_002.jpg (b).
- Six leaves from a Tours Bible., Eleventh century.; Size: Fragment 1/ I.A: 205 x 281 mm (205 x 205 mm incomplete). Fragment 2/ I.B: 207 x 281 mm (134 X 207 mm incomplete). Fragment 3/ II.C: 9 x 271 mm (9 x 271 mm incomplete). Fragment 4/ II.D: 181 x 270 mm (181 x 270 mm incomplete). Fragment 5/ III.E: 257 x 142/121 mm (162 x 88 mm incomplete). Fragment 6/ III.F: 257 x 120 mm (170 x 120 mm incomplete). (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Description: Fragments from a Tours Bible, written in Latin on parchment in a late Carolingian/ early Praegothica script. Fragments contain parts of the books of Genesis, Daniel, and Numbers.
  Provenance: Lost description by Boyd Hill, 1979. Formerly r.36 1-6.
- Two mutilated bifolia from a missal containing parts of Matthew 9 and 18, and Ephesians 4, with some diastematic neumes., Eleventh century.; Size: Bifolium 1: 95 x 166/330 mm (95 x 146 mm incomplete). Bifolium 2: 97 x 187/375 mm (56 x 150 mm incomplete). (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Description: Written in Latin on parchment in a late Carolingian hand. Orange capitals with glosses in a smaller hand. Leaf 1, recto 1 contains Eph. 4:1, 2, 8, verso 1 contains Matt. 9:9, 10, (11?), recto 2 contains Matt. 18: 6,7,8. Leaf 2, recto 1 contains [Matt: 18: 5 -6?], verso 1 contains Matt. 18: 8, 9, 10, recto 2 unknown, verso 2 contains Eph. 4:8, 9, 10, 11, 12. Taken from a binding.
  Provenance: Formerly a.41.
  ID Number: CornellMedMS_021_004.jpg (1a); CornellMedMS_021_003.jpg (1b); CornellMedMS_021_001.jpg (2a); CornellMedMS_021_002.jpg (2b).
- Fragment from a Byzantine patristic manuscript in Greek., Eleventh century.; Size: 270 x 180 mm (250 x 170 mm). (Box 2, Folder 8 bis)
  Description: Written in Greek on parchment in two columns, evidently a homily about St. John Chrysostom.
  Provenance: Acquired by Laurent Ferri, August 2016.
  ID Number:
- Fragment from a manuscript, probably a Bible., Mid-eleventh century.; Size: 34 x 82 mm (34 x 69 mm). (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Description: Written in Latin on parchment in a Carolingian script, possibly containing extracts from the Vulgate Book of Mark 10:33 (‘Ecce ascendimus hieroso…’). Red initial “I”.
  Provenance: Gift of Bruce Ferrini. Formerly folder 12.
  ID Number: CornellMedMS_001.jpg (a).
- Mutilated bifolium containing Haimo of Auxerre’s Homiliae de tempore, 81., Late eleventh century.; Size: 47 x 322/ 198 mm (39 x 180 mm incomplete). (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Description: Written in Latin on parchment in a neat Carolingian script. Ruled in hard-point and this has cut through the parchment a little on leaf 1.
  Provenance: Lost description by Samuel Overstreet, May 1981. Formerly p.34.
  ID Number: CornellMedMS_020_001.jpg (a); CornellMedMS_020_002.jpg (b).
- Three leaves from Bede’s Homiliae, from Italy., Late eleventh or early twelfth century.; Size: 14.1: 420 x 295 mm (336 x 217 mm). 14.2: 418 x 295 mm (328 x 206 mm). 14.3: 419 x 296 mm (354 x 228 mm). (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Description: Written in Latin in an Italian Carolingian script on parchment. Three leaves numbered ciij, cx, cxx, with 43 lines of text in two columns (cxx has 45 lines). Contains part of the homilies for the eighth Sunday after Pentecost. Two decorative initials (“L” f. ciij, “I” f. cx) in yellow, red, blue, and white with interlace and white intertwined tendrils. The loose organization of the decoration is similar to the ornament in a manuscript of the Lives of the Saints attributed to the twelfth century in the Biblioteca Ambrosiana in Milan (MS. B. 49 inf. See M. L. Gengaro and G. V. Guglielmetti, Inventario dei codici decoratie miniati della Biblioteca Ambrosiana, Florence: Olscheki, 1968, pl. 49, pp. 51-52).
  Provenance: Formerly Calkins no. 20; De Ricci, II, 1240, B. 63a; folder 14 (1-3). Brought in 1888 in Lucca for the A. D. White library.
- Single Fragment on vellum, Text by Augustine, from Italy., Circa 1100; Size: 200 x 150 mm. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Description: Written in Latin in an Italian Carolingian script on parchment. Contains part of the "Expositio in Evangelium Iohannis" of Augustine.
  Provenance: Acquired by Laurent Ferri in July 2014.
- Leaf from the Acta Martyrii, including the martyrs of Sebaste., Late eleventh to twelfth century.; Size: 431 x 321/284 mm (406 x 241 mm). (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Description: One leaf in Latin in a Praegothica script on parchment. Beginning: ‘donis multis habere faciam…’, and ending: ‘animas deo reddentes dicebant. Anima’. Text differs from Acta Sanctorum.
  Provenance: Formerly folder 17.
- Mutilated bifolium of an Old Testament capitula and Augustine’s Hipponiensis episcopi Epistulae from chapter 21, De libro Ezechielis, possibly from England., Eleventh to twelfth century.; Size: 311 x 322/211 mm (239 x 194 mm). (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Description: Written in Latin on parchment in a Praegothica script. Contains Old Testament capitula in Latin in two columns recto and verso of 1, and one column (of originally two column page) of Augustine’s Hipponiensis episcopi Epistulae on recto and verso of 2. Red initials and chapter numbers.
  Provenance: Formerly folder 56.
- Leaf, possibly from a service book., Eleventh to twelfth century.; Size: 342 x 231 mm (252 x 170 mm). (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Description: Written in Latin on parchment in a Praegothica script, bordering on Textualis. Red rubrication and initials, including a large “F” with pen work. Two glosses in separate hands in the bottom margins.
  Provenance: Formerly folder 63.
- Leaf, possibly from a service book., Eleventh to twelfth century.; Size: 291 x 215 mm (209 x 147 mm). (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Description: Written in Latin on parchment with red capitals and rubrication. Two decorated initials in red, blue, and green (and yellow?) ink; “D” on recto, “C” on verso. Faded fourteenth-century scripts in the bottom margin.
  Provenance: Formerly folder 62.
- Hymnal leaf (or antiphonary?) with diastematic neumes., Late eleventh to early twelfth century.; Size: 216 x 144 mm (192 x 115 mm). (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Description: Written in Latin on parchment in a late Carolingian script with some Praegothica features. Some faded marginal glossing and red capitals and rubrics.
  Provenance: Lost description by Ceclia Schautz?, May 1981. Formerly a.20.
  ID Number: CornellMedMS_006_001.jpg (a); CornellMedMS_006_002.jpg (b).
- Music fragment from a hymnal with pre-square notation., Late eleventh to twelfth century.; Size: 81 x 223 mm (184 x 76 mm). Four staves: 12.0 mm. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Description: Written in Latin on parchment in a late Carolingian script. Score written with four line staves and using pre-square notation. Rubrics and lines in red ink.
  Provenance: Formerly h.47.
  ID Number: CornellMedMS_002_002.jpg (a); CornellMedMS_002_001.jpg (b).
- Fragment from St. Augustine, Expositio in evangelium Johannis., Circa 1100.; Size: 160 x 210 mm (140 x 170 mm). (Box 2, Folder 14bis)
  Description: Parts of Tractatus 15, cap. IV and Tractatus 25. Written in Latin in double columns on vellum in Carolingian minuscule script. Rubrics in red ink.
  Provenance: Acquired by Laurent Ferri in 2014.
- Two leaves from a Bible containing the Books of Ezra/ Nehemiah (folio 4) and Judith (folio 5)., Twelfth century.; Size: Folio 4: 430 x 307 mm (407 x 260 mm incomplete). Folio 5: 428 x 308 mm (409 x 250 mm). Fragment torn from top of folio 5: 47 x 161 mm. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Description: Written in Latin in a Praegothica script. Two leaves from a Bible on parchment in two columns. The top corner of the second folio has been torn off. It remains with the collection and has some stitching remaining.
  Provenance: Formerly De Ricci B63b; folder 15 (1-2).
- Mutilated bifolium from a liturgical manuscript containing Psalm XIII (XIV?) with diastematic neumes., Mid-twelfth century.; Size: 49 x 282 mm (19 x 143 mm incomplete). (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Description: Written in Latin on parchment in a Praegothica script. Including chants for Psalm XIII (and possibly XIV) indicated by interlinear diastematic neumes.
  Provenance: Formerly q.35.
  ID Number: CornellMedMS_019_002.jpg (a); CornellMedMS_019_001.jpg (b).
- Fragment of a leaf with music for epiphany, with pre-square notation., Twelfth century.; Size: 222 x 79 mm (189 x 79mm). Four staves: 12.5 mm. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Description: Fragment in Latin featuring pre-square notation on four line staves. Written in a Praegothica script with red rubrication.
  Provenance: Formerly folder 12.
  ID Number: CornellMedMS_023_002.jpg (a); CornellMedMS_023_001.jpg (b).
- One mutilated bifolium and three fragments from a breviary with diastematic neumes., Twelfth century.; Size: Fragment 1: 78 x 144 mm (49 x 109 mm incomplete). Fragment 2: 91 x 162/145 mm (91 x 115 mm incomplete). Fragment 3: 93 x 156 mm (93 x 112 mm incomplete). Bifolia 4: 231 x 151/284 mm (191 x 119 mm). (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Description: Written in Latin on parchment in a late Carolingian script with some Praegothica features (uncial “D” and enclosed “G”). Red capitals and rubrication, and chants with diastematic neumes. Including feasts of saints Vitus, Lawrence, Hermes, Augustine, John the Baptist, Martial, Ludmila, and Benedict.
  Provenance: Lost description by Margot Fassler, May 1979. Formerly f.25 (1-4).
  ID Number: CornellMedMS_024_009.jpg (1a); CornellMedMS_024_010.jpg (1b); CornellMedMS_024_006.jpg (2a); CornellMedMS_024_005.jpg (2b); CornellMedMS_024_007.jpg (3a); CornellMedMS_024_008.jpg (3b); CornellMedMS_024_001.jpg (4a); CornellMedMS_024_002.jpg (4b); CornellMedMS_024_003.jpg (4c); CornellMedMS_024_004.jpg (4d).
- Two leaves featuring the offices of saints Leo, Peter and Paul, James, Nazarius and Celsus, Abdon and Seunen., Twelfth century.; Size: Leaf 1: 270 x 216/196 mm (254 x 171 mm). Leaf 2: 269 x 216 mm (257 x 171 mm). (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Description: Written in Latin on parchment in a neat Praegothica, close to Carolingian, script. Red initials and rubrics. Later marginal notes added in black ink. Both leaves cut off at the bottom and crenelated.
  Provenance: Lost description by Fred Jonassen?, 1980. Formerly n.32 (1-2).
- Binding strip containing text from the Vulgate Bible, Luke 2., Twelfth century.; Size: 65 x 345 mm (21 x 231 mm). (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Description: Written in Latin on parchment in a late Carolingian, early Praegothica script. Text in two columns. Text on verso damaged from being glued into binding.
  Provenance: Formerly folder k.49.
- Fragment taken from a binding from an unidentified book., Twelfth century.; Size: 105 x 392 mm. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Description: Written in Latin on parchment with red rubrication and a decorated initial “P”. Very faded text, probably in a Praegothica script.
  Provenance: Donated by Fleda Meyers. Formerly f.56.
- Leaf from Augutine’s De doctrina christiana (ii. 38-40 incomplete)., Twelfth century.; Size: 271 x 183 mm (211 x 123 mm). (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Description: Written in Latin on parchment in a Praegothica script. Removed from the cover of Purbach’s Theorocae novae planetarum in The History of Science, 1591. Parchment tabs surviving on bottom of page.
  Provenance: Lost description by Janet Durholz, 1986 and Kelly Wickham-Crowley, 1981. Formerly folder s.37.
- One mutilated bifolium with commentary on Deuteronomy 27 and 32., Late twelfth century.; Size: 146 x 196/386 mm (94 x 140 mm incomplete). (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Description: Mutilated bifolium in Latin on parchment with text on flesh side only, taken from a binding. In a Praegothica, reaching Textualis, script (with almost exclusive use of uncial “d” and the Tironian nota).
  Provenance: Lost descriptions by Paul Reveley?, 1982, and Florence Newman, 1979. Formerly l.30.
- Leaf from a Book of Hours with pen drawing of God the Father with crucified Christ., Late twelfth century.; Size: 121 x 82 mm (84 x 52 mm) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Description: Written in Latin on parchment in a Praegothica script with some red rubrication. Illustration on recto of God the father with the crucified Christ, and of verso of Christ with globus cruciger.
  Provenance: Formerly folder 61.
- Two bifolia from the so-called “Psalter of St. Mary”, with 15 verses of rhyming devotional poetry in Old French from France., Early thirteenth century, ca. 1220.; Size: Bifolium 1: 145 x 105/200 mm (114 x 71 mm). Bifolium 2: 145 x 117/198 mm (116 x 78 mm). (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Description: Written in Latin verse with 15 verses of rhyming devotional poetry in Old French, in a Textualis Formata script and on parchment. Single column with 22 lines per page. Two large three-line initials, one in red, the other in blue, with contrasting penwork extending into the margins; over fifty initials A’s alternating red and blue. Certain linguistic traits may imply a north-eastern dialect.
  Provenance: Purchased in 2013 by Laurent Ferri.
  ID Number: CornellMedMS_011_008.jpg; CornellMedMS_011_005.jpg; CornellMedMS_011_007.jpg; CornellMedMS_011_006.jpg; CornellMedMS_011_004.jpg; CornellMedMS_011_003.jpg; CornellMedMS_011_002.jpg; CornellMedMS_011_001.jpg.
- Three bindings strips from an unidentified manuscript., Early thirteenth century.; Size: 1: 290 x 42 mm. 2: 144 x 49 mm. 3: 144 x 34 mm. (Box 3, Folder 2)